Discover your true nature.
The Wild Robot is a animation, science fiction,
family film directed by Chris Sanders.
After a shipwreck, an intelligent robot called Roz is
stranded on an uninhabited island.
To survive the harsh environment, Roz bonds with the island's
animals and cares for an orphaned baby goose.
Roz / Rummage (voice), played by Lupita Nyong'o.
Fink (voice), played by Pedro Pascal.
Brightbill (voice), played by Kit Connor.
Longneck (voice), played by Bill Nighy.
Vontra (voice), played by Stephanie Hsu.
Paddler (voice), played by Matt Berry.
The Wild Robot is a 2024 American animated science fiction film based on the
2016 novel by Peter Brown and produced by DreamWorks Animation.
It was written and directed by Chris Sanders and features the voices of Lupita Nyong'o, Pedro Pascal, Kit
Connor, Bill Nighy, Stephanie Hsu, Matt Berry, Ving Rhames, Mark Hamill, and Catherine O'Hara.
The film follows a service robot shipwrecked on an island who must adapt to her surroundings, build
relationships with the local wildlife, and become the adoptive mother of an orphaned goose.
DreamWorks Animation bought the screenplay before
the first novel's release in 2016.
Sanders first encountered the original book through his daughter and was
offered an opportunity to direct a film adaptation at DreamWorks.
The film's visuals use a watercolor aesthetic, inspired by classic
Disney animated films and the works of Hayao Miyazaki.
Kris Bowers composed the score, marking his first
score for a fully animated film.
Development took four years on a budget of $78 million.
The Wild Robot premiered at the 49th Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2024,
and was released in the United States on September 27, by Universal Pictures.
The film received critical acclaim from critics who praised it for its
writing, animation, score, emotional depth, and voice acting.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $334.5 million worldwide.
Among its accolades, it received nine Annie Awards (including Best Animated Feature), won Best Animated Feature at the Critics' Choice Awards and Producers Guild of
America Awards, and was nominated for four Golden Globe Awards and three Academy Awards, becoming DreamWorks' most-nominated film at the latter ceremony.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of villain, robot, based on
children's book, female villain, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.